A Guide to the Papers of the Dillard Family, 1717-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Papers of James Hardy Dillard
  - Subseries C: Special Subjects
    - Dillard University and Atlanta University materials; Dillard University and Flint Goodridge Hospital (of Dillard University)
      - Miscellaneous materials re: Dillard University, 1930-1955 (Box 18)
        Includes The Modern Hospital, Nov. 1932 (5 copies); Flint-Goodridge Hospital, Superintendent's Report, 1943; Inauguration of William Nelson as President, program, 1937; The Dillard Bulletin, April, May, and Dec. 1937; May 1948; Dillard University, Summary Report (Workshop on Problems and Opportunities Confronting Negro Youth) 1945; An American Dilemma-The Negro Problem and Modern Democracy; Dedication of Lawless Memorial Chapel, 1955; The American Missionary Association and Dillard University, used at the opening of Dillard University, 1935; Court Bouillon, Dillard University, Spring, 1936 & 1937; The Spirit of James H. Dillard, Founders Day address, 1936; Straight College Bulletin, March 1930; The Arts Quarterly, Apr-June 1937 (2 copies) and July-Sept. 1937; Dillard University Calendar, 1944; Programs and speeches for Cornerstone Laying, 1934; miscellaneous clippings, invitation, announcements, etc., photographs of Dillard University-its construction; and Dillard University Up to 1945, booklet.
      - Atlanta University: Financial Statement and Report of the President, 1937-1938, 1939-1940 (Box 18)
    - Ministers Institute/Preachers Institute
      - Miscellaneous materials re: Ministers Institute/Preachers Institute, Minutes and announcements, 1921-1934 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous materials re: Southern Education Foundation, 1937-1940 (Box 19)
        Includes Minutes of meetings, July 1937; April 1938; January 1940 (2 copies); Annual Report of the President, 1938, 1940; and Examination of Accounts, 1938; 1939.
      - General Education Board, 1916, 1931, 1940 (Box 19)
        Bi-monthly report, June 1940; Occasional Paper #3, "A Modern School," 1916; and Annual Report, American Missionary Association, 1931.
  - Subseries D: Poems and Notes
    - Poetry, Verses to Varro I and II, by James H. Dillard, 1899 (Box 20)
    - Three booklets of poetry by James H. Dillard, 1903, n.d. (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous poems handwritten by James H. Dillard, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous poems, by or of interest to James H. Dillard, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Law notes from Washington and Lee, 1876-1877 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous teaching notes and two Latin plays, ca. 1880 (Box 20)
    - Manuscripts on Vergil, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Subseries E: Speeches, Articles, Letters to the Editor
    - Originals of speeches, articles, and letters to the editor, handwritten by James H. Dillard, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 21)
    - Originals and carbons of speeches, articles, and letters to the editor, typed by James H. Dillard, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 22)
    - Speech outlines, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 23)
    - Lists of addresses, n.d., miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Diaries and accounts of James H. Dillard
    - Miscellaneous passports (Box 24)
      3 - James H. Dillard; 2 - Avarene B. Dillard; 1 - George Dillard; and extra passport photographs.
    - Diary-Journal (JHD), 1880-1894 (Box 24)
      Papers with description of "Farmers Delight."
    - Outward and Homeward Bound, diary (JHD), May-Sept., 1906 (Box 24)
    - Diary, May 1919-Jan. 1921 (Box 24)
    - Diary, Jan. 1921-Jan. 1923 (Box 24)
    - Diary, Jan. 1923-March 1925 (Box 24)
    - My Travels, journal, Dec. 1923-April 1924 (Box 24)
    - My Trip Abroad, journal, June-Sept. 1926 (Box 24)
    - Ledger, account, Sept. 1878-Oct. 1882 (Box 24)
    - Address, appointment book, 1909 (Box 24)
    - Mathematics work book, 1878 (Box 24)
    - Five small note pads for Greek and Math (Box 24)
    - Autograph book, Princeton (James Dillard), 1847 (Box 24)
    - Autograph book, Washington and Lee (James H. Dillard), 1874 (Box 24)
  - Subseries H: Reprints of articles by James H. Dillard (Box 25-26)
    - Printed booklets and addresses by James H. Dillard, 1921-1940 (Box 26)
      Papers by the Way, 1940 (16 copies); Agnes Scott College Bulletin, Dedication Addresses, Wallace Buttrick Hall (2 copies); "Culture At the Crossroads," 1924 (2 copies); "Booker T. Washington, A Christian Philosopher," 1925; "The Humanity of Armstrong," 1921.
  - Subseries I: Newspaper articles by or about James H. Dillard
    - Newspaper articles re: James H. Dillard (Box 27)
    - Newspaper articles and letters to the editor by James H. Dillard (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous newspapers and articles of interest to James H. Dillard (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 28)
    - Small slate blackboard (Box 29)
    - Membership book, Woman's Auxiliary to Board of Missions, 1891-1896 (Box 29)
    - Journal articles about and of interest to James H. Dillard (Box 29)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Major James Dillard (Box 37)
  - Large portrait photographs of James H. Dillard (Box 37)
  - Small photographs of James H. Dillard (Box 37)
  - Large photographs of James H. Dillard with other people (Box 37)
  - Large portrait photographs of friends of James H. Dillard (Box 37)
  - Snapshots of members of Dillard family and friends (Box 38)
  - Snapshots of James H. Dillard with friends and groups (Box 38)
  - photographs of Hardy C. Dillard (Box 38)
  - Photo of University of Virginia Law Review with Hardy C. Dillard (Box 38)
  - photographs of members of Dillard family (identified) (Box 38)
  - photographs of Dillard family and friends (many unidentified) (Box 38)
  - photographs of Dillard family and friends (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous snapshots (Box 39)
  - photographs of "Park Hill" (Dillard's Home) (Box 40)
  - photographs of Annie Harmanson (Box 40)
  - photographs of Avarene (Rose) Budd Dillard (Box 40)
  - photographs of members of the Budd family (Box 40)
  - Pages from photo album of Avarene Budd Dillard (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified photographs, mostly from Budd family collection (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous Budd family photographs (in framed cases) (Box 42)
  - Budd family photo album (Box 42)
  - Four photo albums of vacations: Savannah - Sea Islands; North Florida; South Florida; and Weekend at Battery Park (Box 42)
  - photographs from Virgin Islands (Box 42)
  - photographs of the Virginia Players (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of large school groups (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of groups, scenes, and buildings (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous prints (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous negatives (Box 43)
- Series V: Avarene Budd Dillard
  - Subseries A: Early Materials
    - Mt. Holyoke, Class of '87; Avarene Budd Dillard, 1887-1949 (Box 44)
      Includes Classbook of '87, Autograph book and class correspondence.
    - Avarene Budd Dillard, D.A.R. materials and University of Virginia summer school certificate, 1918 (Box 44)
    - Correspondence to Mrs. A.E. Budd, 1882-1904 (Box 44)
    - A.E. Budd; early correspondence and letters of recommendation, 1835-1842 (Box 44)
      Also includes debate topic, 1937.
    - Miscellaneous materials 1841, 1882 (Box 44)
      University of Pennsylvania catalogue, 1841; resolutions on death of A.E. Budd, 1882; and miscellaneous materials.
    - James Lippincott; licenses and certificates, 1862, 1866 (Box 44)
    - Mrs. James (Carra) Lippincott; correspondence and miscellaneous materials, 1876-1925 (Box 44)
    - Notes on Payson familiy lineage and other relations, n.d. (Box 44)
      Also includes a letter to a Miss Payson, 1850.
    - Miscellaneous materials, 1890, 1936 (Box 44)
      Phrenological Delineation of Avarene L. Budd, 1890; and Historical Sketches of Mt. Holly and Vicinity, Pamphlets 1 and 2, 1936.
    - Avarene B. Dillard, certificate, members of National Geographic Society, 1939 (Box 44)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1874-1889 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence, "Love letters" from James Dillard to Ava Budd, 1898 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence, "Love letters" from James Dillard to Ava Budd, 1899 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence, 1899-1900 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence, 1904, 1906, 1907 (Box 47)
    - Correspondence, 1908-1909 (Box 47)
    - Correspondence, 1910-1915 (Box 47)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 47)
    - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, 1921 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, 1922 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 49)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1936 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 50)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 52)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 52)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 52)
    - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 52)
    - Business: receipts, bills, etc. (Box 52)
    - Business: taxes, etc. (Box 52)
    - Civic and charity correspondence (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous invitations and telegrams re: birth of grandchildren (Box 52)
  - Subseries C: Scrapbooks and Notebooks
    - Scrapbook: materialis while at Girl's High School, Philadelphia, 1896-1897 (Box 53)
    - Scrapbook: miscellaneous materials while in New Orleans, 1898-1899 (Box 53)
    - Notebooks and pads, 1886 (Box 53)
      Poems at Mt. Holyoke, 1886; Jone's Greek Prose; and miscellaneous poems, prose, notes, etc.
    - Clippings pasted over other pages (Box 53)
      Literary References; Applied Science; Interesting Facts in Science; and Historical References.
    - Two books with clipped poems (Box 54)
    - Letters to Ruth, Vol. I, II, and III (Box 54)
    - The Physician's Daily Pocket Recorder (A.E. Budd), miscellaneous use by Avarene B. Dillard (Box 54)
    - Twenty miscellaneous composition books and pads, Avarene B. Dillard (Box 54)
    - Autograph book to Miss Budd from her class, 1887 (Box 54)
  - Subseries D: Diaries and memo pads of Avarene Budd Dillard
    - Diaries, 1924-1949, 11 volumes. (Box 55)
    - Three address books (Box 55)
    - Memo book; visiting list (Box 55)
    - Memo book; cards and presents (Box 55)
    - Memo book; miscellaneous, Carra Lippincott (Box 55)
    - Four miscellaneous booklets (Box 55)
    - Memo book, "Worthwhile Thoughts," (Box 55)
  - Subseries E: Ledger accounts
    - Ledger accounts, incomplete, 1904-1949, 20 volumes. (Box 56)
    - Checkbook stubs, Avarene Budd Dillard (Box 57)
    - Personal accounts, Avarene Budd Dillard, Jan. 1944-Aug. 1945; Aug. 1945-Sept. 1946 (Box 57)
    - House accounts, Avarene Budd Dillard, Dec. 1941-Dec. 1943; Jan. 1944-June 1946; June 1946-May 1947; May 1947-April 1948; April 1948-May 1949; and May 1949-July 1950. (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous checks (Box 57)
    - Two savings account books (Box 57)
- Series VI: Family Bibles and Testaments
  - New Testament, English and German (Jams H. Dillard), 1872 (Box 58)
  - New Testament, English and Spanish (James H. Dillard), 1872 (Box 58)
  - The Book of Psalms (James H. Dillard), 1884 (Box 58)
  - The Sacred Books of the Old and New Testaments, part 17, The Book of Psalms (James H. Dillard), 1935 (Box 58)
  - The First and Second Book of the Maccabees (James H. Dillard) (Box 58)
  - The Holy Bible (Joseph Haight), 1869 (Box 58)
  - The Holy Bible (Mary C. Harmanson), 1864 (Box 58)
  - The Holy Bible (Sallie Lightfoot Johnson), 1896 (Box 58)
  - The Holy Bible (Box 58)
  - Common Prayer, The Hymnal (Avarene B. Dillard), 1908 (Box 59)
  - Book of Common Prayer, Hymnal (Mary C. Harmanson), 1867 (Box 59)
  - Book of Common Prayer (James H. Dillard), 1880 (Box 59)
  - The Hymnal (Carra Garrett), 1889 (Box 59)
  - Book of Common Prayer (A.T. Tabb), 1849 (Box 59)
  - Book of Common Prayer, 1855 (Box 59)
  - Hymns and Songs (Avarene B. Dillard), 1875 (Box 59)
  - A Devotional Diary, 1925 (Box 59)
  - The Christ of History by John Young, 1866 (Box 59)
  - The Doctrine of Life for the New Jerusalem (Avarene B. Dillard) (Box 59)
  - Advice to Christian Parents by John Hersey, 1838 (Box 59)
  - Epitome Historiae Sacrae, 1822 (Box 59)
  - The Secret of Christ our Life by Andrew Murray, 1934 (Box 59)
  - Prayer book (no binding) (Box 59)
  - Little Sermons by Edna Carter, 1908 (Box 59)
  - Les Saint Evangiles de Notre Seigneur Jesus-Christ et Les Actest Des Apotres, 1914 (Box 59)
  - Summary Exposition of the Doctrine of the New Church (Box 59)
- Series VII: George and Hardy C. Dillard
  - Subseries A: Miscellaneous materials of Hardy and George Dillard
    - Correspondence, Hardy C. Dillard, 1906-1927 (Box 60)
      "Goat" Dillard letter, 1919.
    - Correspondeonce, Hardy C. Dillard, 1930-1954, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, Affair with Page Bird at Sweet Briar College, 1928 (Box 60)
    - Correspondence re: Sale of land in Louisiana, Hardy C. Dillard, 1942-1943 (Box 60)
    - Class of '27 Law Letter, Hardy C. Dillard, 1932 (Box 60)
    - Debating materials, Hardy C. Dillard, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous grade reports, 5th grade, Law School, Hardy C. Dillard (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous school work papers, Hardy C. Dillard (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous clippings re: Hardy C. Dillard, 1945-1963 (Box 60)
      Includes CASALOG, Civil Affairs Newspaper, 5 issues, 1945; Judicial Deference to State Department Suggestions by M.H. Cardozo, 1963, and The Haggadah of Passover, for members of the Armed Forces, 1945.
    - Miscellaneous clippings and other materials, Hardy C. Dillard (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, 1913, 1919, 1922, 1936, 1937, 1938, 1942-1943, n.d. (Box 60)
      Includes undated correspondence re: trip to Africa, 1924.
    - Pencil drawings by George Dillard at age 4 (Box 60)
    - Play by Carra Garrett (Dillard), 1919 (Box 60)
    - College notebooks and memo pads, Hardy C. Dillard (Box 61)
    - College notebooks of Hardy S. (Judge) Dillard (Box 61)
    - College papers of Hardy S. Dillard (Box 61)
    - Beta Theta Phi, fraternity magazine, 1926 (Box 61)
    - Maps and guidebooks to England, France, Europe (for soldiers) (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous maps and pamphlets of Sandra Brown (Box 62)
    - School materials on Batles of the American Revolution (Box 62)
    - School project, Explorers of America, Cheryl Bush and Frances Cohn (Box 62)
    - Package of materials for teaching about the U.S. and foreign affairs (Box 62)
    - Scorebook, 1917 baseball team, Episcopal School (Box 62)
    - Virginia Episcopal School, 1957-1958 (Box 62)
    - Political Science Quarterly, Dec. 1963 (Box 62)
    - Rotunda (University of Virginia) Christmas cards (Box 62)
    - Comic book, Black Magic,April-May 1951 (Box 62)
  - Subseries B: Notebooks, Books of Hardy S. Dillard
    - A Virginia Chronology 1585-1783, 1957 (Box 63)
    - Virginia Under Charles I and Cromwell, 1625-1660, 1957 (Box 63)
    - The MLA Style Sheet (Box 63)
    - Kellog's Improved Class Register (gradebook) (Box 63)
    - Three college notebooks (Box 63)
    - College notes and papers, Hardy S. Dillard (Box 63)
    - Correspondence to "Judge" Dillard, 1960 (Box 63)
    - Lifesaving and Water Safety, 1956 (Box 64)
    - Man on Spikes, 1955 (Box 64)
    - An Outline History of the Middle Ages, 1957 (Box 64)
    - The Decline of Rome, 1957 (Box 64)
    - Introducing College Mathematics, 1954 (Box 64)
    - A History of the American Republic, 1955 (Box 64)
    - Defending America, 1941 (Box 64)
  - Subseries C: Military Career of Hardy S. Dillard
    - C.A.X. (Civil Affairs Exercise) materials, Hardy C. Dillard, 1943-1944 (Box 65)
    - C.A.X. (Civil Affairs Exercise) materials, Hardy C. Dillard, 1944, 1943-1945 (Box 66)
    - The Brookings Institution: Major Problems of U.S. Foreign Policy, 1948, 12 items. (Box 67)
    - National War College materials, 1951-1961 (Box 68)
    - Report to the Superintendent by the U.S.M.A. (United States Military Academy) Committee on Service Academics, May 1949 (Box 68)
    - The Commonwealth, June 1939 (Box 68)
    - Materials on French-American relations, 14 items. (Box 69)
    - Material on Soviet Foreign Economic Policy, 1957, 2 items. (Box 69)
    - N.A.T.O. (North Atlantic Treaty Organization) Defense College Record, July 1957 (Box 69)
    - Educational and Cultural Exchange and the Nationality Classrooms, University of Pittsburgh, 1957 (Box 69)
    - Report, James Monroe Bicentennial Commission, 1960 (Box 69)
    - Bronze Algernon Sydney Sullivan Medallion awarded by Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard (Box 69)
    - Bronze Algernon Sydney Sullivan Medallion awarded by the College of William and Mary to James Hardy Dillard (Box 69)
    - Photograph of Mr. J.H. Dillard (Box 69)
    - Black and white print of a nude in a lake, copyright, 1912 (Box 69)
    - Picture of a relief of William Richard Galt with note on back, signed, Elizabeth Galt Welles to Dr. Dillard (Box 69)
    - Unknown set of family photographs of young female child (Box 69)
    - Photograph of J.H. Dillard and 5 other men (Box 69)
    - Photograph of three unidentified young men (Box 69)
    - Miscellaneous materials re: Madison Hall, University of Virginia, Y.M.C.A. 1958-1960 (Box 70)
    - The Brookings Institution Seminar, Problems of U.S. Foreign Policy, 1947 (Box 70)
  - University Senate Committee (University of Virginia), steering committee (Box 71)
    Materials re: selecting a President to succeed President Darden, 1958-1959.
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous Materials
  - Subseries A: Yearbooks
    - Briar Patch, Sweet Briar Yearbook (Carra Garrett), 1916 (Box 72)
    - Helianthus, Randolph-Macon Woman's College Yearbook (Carra Garrett), 1917 (Box 72)
    - The Jinger Jar, St. Anne's Yearbook (Carra G. Dillard), 1928 (Box 72)
    - Handy Book (notebook), Carra Dillard (Box 72)
    - Whispers, Episcopal High School Yearbook (George Dillard), 1915 (Box 72)
    - Whispers, Episcopal High School Yearbook (George Dillard), 1916 (Box 72)
    - The Roland V. Vaughn Private Collection, 1931 (Box 72)
  - Subseries B: Miscellaneous postcards (Box 73)
  - Subseries C: Greeting Cards
    - Miscellaneous Christmas cards to Dr. and Mrs. James H. Dillard (Box 74)
    - Miscellaneous greeting cards to Mrs. James H. Dillard (Box 74)
    - Christmas cards to Mr. and Mrs. Hardy C. Dillard, 1964 (Box 74)
  - Subseries D: Odds and Ends
    - Sewing Society of Christ Church, 1918 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous club announcements, Fortnightly Club and others, 1916-1931 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous materials, odds and ends, scraps, etc. (Box 76-77)
- Oversize Materials
  - Degree from Washington and Lee to James H. Dillard in Greek, 1874.
  - Degree from Washington and Lee to James H. Dillard in Natural Philosophy, 1876.
  - Degree from Mount Holyoke Female Seminary to Avarene L. Budd, 1887.
  - Certificate of appointment to Board of Visitors of William and Mary to James H. Dillard, 1938.
  - Blueprints, sketches, drawings, and plans for a house for Hardy C. Dillard, designed by Edmund Campbell, Architect, July-August, 1940.
  - Certificate of membership of Miss Avarene Lippincott Budd from the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1894 October 4.
  - Certificate of membership of Andrews E. Budd from The District Medical Society of the County of the Burlington, New Jersey, 1878 April 9.
  - Certificate of completion of the course of study in the High School Department of Tulane University of Louisiana - L. Sophie Newcomb Memorial College, of Katharine Harmanson Dillard, 1901 June 18
  - Diploma of the New Orleans Free Kindergarten Association to Katharine Harmanson Dillard, 1904 May 27.
  - Certificate of completion of the course of study in the High School Department of Tulane University of Louisiania - L. Sophie Newcomb Memorial College, of Elizabeth Nicholson Dillard, 1902 May 27.
  - Certificate of the Jamestown Exposition Company for the 1907 Jamestown Tercentennial Exposition naming the Honorable Jas. H. Dillard as an Honorary Advisor, 1906 October 17.
  - Appointment of James H. Dillard as a member of the State Board of Education, Second Congressional District, signed by the governor of Louisiana, 1904 September 28.
  - Bachelor of Arts Degree of James Dillard from the College of New Colon (Neo-Casareinsis)
  - Unsigned Certificate from the Societas Cliosophica (a fraternity?) in the College of New Colon (Neo-Casariensis)
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the prescribed course of study in English in the School of English Language and Literature, 1874 June 24.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the entire course of study in the School of Latin, 1874 June 24.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the prescribed course of study in French in the School of Modern Languages, 1875 June 23.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the entire course of study in the School of Mathematics, 1875 June 23.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the prescribed course of study in German in the School of Modern Languages, 1875 June 23.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction in the entire course of study in the School of Moral Philosophy, 1875 June 23.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction of the entire course of study in the School of English, 1876 June 21.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction of the entire course of study in the School of Modern History, 1876 June 21.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University to James Hardy Dillard for completion with Distinction of the Rhetoric Course of study in the School of Moral Philosophy and Better Letters, 1876 June 21.
  - Master of Arts diploma from Washington and Lee University, to James Hardy Dillard, 1876 June 21.
  - Bachelor of Law Degree from Washington and Lee University, to James Hardy Dillard, 1877 June 27.
  - Doctor of Laws Degree from Tulane University of Louisiana to James Hardy Dillard, 1908 March 13.
  - Honorary Doctor of Laws Degree from Southwestern at Memphis to James Hardy Dillard, 1932 June 7.
  - Doctor of Laws Degree (honorary?) from Liberia College, Monrovia, Liberia, 1923 February 1.
  - Certificate commissioning James H. Dillard a member of the Board of Visitors of the College of Willam and Mary, 1938 March 12.
  - Doctor of Laws degree from Harvard College (Honorary) to James Hardy Dillard (in red tube), 1923 June 21.
  - Doctor in the Medical Arts degree from the University of Pennsylvania to Andrews E. Budd and seal of the University of Pennsylvania in green container formerly attached by a ribbon, 1842 March 26.
  - Certificate from the College of William and Mary in Virginia for the Algernon Sydney Sulivan Award to James Hardy Dillard, 1927 June 7.
  - Certificate from Washington and Lee University for The Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award to James Hardy Dillard, 1931 June 9.
  - Map of "Subdivision of Rugby Hills" made from Deed Book, 1926 January-1928 August 27.
  - Photograph of Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity
  - Sketch autographed by subject, Julis Rosenwald